<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SQL Injection on my Blog site</title><link>https://santhoshvardan-blog.vercel.app/categories/sql-injection/</link><description>Recent content in SQL Injection on my Blog site</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 12:34:30 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://santhoshvardan-blog.vercel.app/categories/sql-injection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sql Injection Vulnerbility With Filter Bypass via XML Encoding</title><link>https://santhoshvardan-blog.vercel.app/portswigger/sql-injection/portswigger-sql-injection-vulnerbility-bypass-xml-encoding/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 12:34:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://santhoshvardan-blog.vercel.app/portswigger/sql-injection/portswigger-sql-injection-vulnerbility-bypass-xml-encoding/</guid><description>The above image is lab description from the above description
we know that there is a database that contains username and password to solve the lab we have to retrieve the username and password and login to their account. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the hint
hint A web application firewall (WAF) will block requests that contain obvious signs of a SQL injection attack. You'll need to find a way to obfuscate your malicious query to bypass this filter.</description></item><item><title>Sql Injection Vulnerbility in Where Clause Allowing Retrieval of Hidden Data</title><link>https://santhoshvardan-blog.vercel.app/portswigger/sql-injection/portswigger-sql-injection-vulnerbility-where-clause/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 12:31:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://santhoshvardan-blog.vercel.app/portswigger/sql-injection/portswigger-sql-injection-vulnerbility-where-clause/</guid><description>in this description it&amp;rsquo;s saying that there is a SQL vuln in product category filter , to solve this lab we need to perform a SQL injection that causes application to display unreleases products
this is the website dashboard since it&amp;rsquo;s mentioned that there is a vulnerability in product category let&amp;rsquo;s select the product category and capture the request in burp suite
SELECT * FROM products WHERE category = &amp;lsquo;Gifts&amp;rsquo; AND released = 1</description></item><item><title>Sql Injection Vulnerbility Allowing Login Bypass</title><link>https://santhoshvardan-blog.vercel.app/portswigger/sql-injection/portswigger-sql-injection-vulnerbility-allowing-login-bypass/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 12:28:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://santhoshvardan-blog.vercel.app/portswigger/sql-injection/portswigger-sql-injection-vulnerbility-allowing-login-bypass/</guid><description>In this lab we need to by pass login as administrator to complete the lab We know our username is administrator
The Website:
Let&amp;rsquo;s go to login page and try some details and capture the request in burpsuite
here we can see a post request captured in this burp let&amp;rsquo;s send this to repeater and play with some parameters
from the request
csrf=HsLJjSGkCiFEw8OYoi4IjOfa8mV2lQlv: - csrf stands for Cross-Site Request Forgery token.</description></item><item><title>Sql Injection Union Attack Determining the Number of Columns Returned by the Query</title><link>https://santhoshvardan-blog.vercel.app/portswigger/sql-injection/portswigger-sql-database-union-attack/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 12:19:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://santhoshvardan-blog.vercel.app/portswigger/sql-injection/portswigger-sql-database-union-attack/</guid><description>from the lab description we know that there is SQL vulnerability in product category filter , to solve the lab we need to perform a union attack that determine number of columns
let&amp;rsquo;s access the lab The website
to display null values we need to use the payload &amp;lsquo;+UNION+SELECT+NULL&amp;ndash; if 1 column in ther if 2 colums are there then we need tp use 2 NULLs so on
i&amp;rsquo;ve started with null value and i got internal server error let&amp;rsquo;s try 2</description></item><item><title>Sql Injection Querying Oracle</title><link>https://santhoshvardan-blog.vercel.app/portswigger/sql-injection/portswigger-sql-database-querying-oracle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 16:42:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://santhoshvardan-blog.vercel.app/portswigger/sql-injection/portswigger-sql-database-querying-oracle/</guid><description>From the lab description we know that there is SQL vulnerability in product category and to solve this lab we need to display database version string
And this is a ORACLE database
Refer to SQL cheatsheet here
https://portswigger.net/web-security/sql-injection/cheat-sheet
TO retrieve the database version and contents these are the payloads available here
Now let&amp;rsquo;s access the website
From the website if we select the different categories mentioned here by selecting different categories the website is refining our search</description></item><item><title>Sql Injection Querying</title><link>https://santhoshvardan-blog.vercel.app/portswigger/sql-injection/portswigger-sql-database-querying-non-oracle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 16:38:06 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://santhoshvardan-blog.vercel.app/portswigger/sql-injection/portswigger-sql-database-querying-non-oracle/</guid><description>From the lab description we know that There is SQL vulnerability in product category filter. To solve the lab we need to display the database version string
Here the database is My SQL , Let&amp;rsquo;s head over to SQL cheat sheet for payloads refer to sql sheet for here
here are the available list of payloads we can use for different types of databases
Let&amp;rsquo;s access the lab
the same thing we have here it will refine your search based on the category you select for detail walkthrough refer to</description></item><item><title>Sql Injection Listing Databse Contents</title><link>https://santhoshvardan-blog.vercel.app/portswigger/sql-injection/portswigger-sql-database-listing-oracle-databse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 16:33:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://santhoshvardan-blog.vercel.app/portswigger/sql-injection/portswigger-sql-database-listing-oracle-databse/</guid><description>From the LAB description there is a SQL Vulnerability in the product category filter and to complete this lab we need to log in as administrator
this lab contains oracle database refer to SQL CHEAT SHEET for payloads
HINT: On Oracle databases, every SELECT statement must specify a table to select FROM. If your UNION SELECT attack does not query from a table, you will still need to include the FROM keyword followed by a valid table name.</description></item><item><title>Sql Injection</title><link>https://santhoshvardan-blog.vercel.app/portswigger/sql-injection/portswigger-sql-database-listing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 16:26:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://santhoshvardan-blog.vercel.app/portswigger/sql-injection/portswigger-sql-database-listing/</guid><description>From the lab description This lab contains SQL injection Vulnerability in Product category filter to solve this lab we need to login as administrator this lab contains non oracle databases
refer to SQL CHEAT SHEET for payloads Let&amp;rsquo;s access the lab like as usual we&amp;rsquo;ve intercepted the request and sent it to repeater now let&amp;rsquo;s check number of columns and determine the data type of those columns to perform a union attack</description></item></channel></rss>